## **Mahmoud Roshdy Moawad**

### **Backup & Data Management**

Administrator

Contact

### **Email:**

mahmmoud.roshdy@yahoo.com

#### Address

Kuwait-Farwanya

#### **Phone:**

+965-96962259

# Nationality

Egyptian

### LinkedIn profile:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahmoud-roshdy-moawwad-3bb02328/

#### **About Me**

A versatile, analytical and hardworking senior system Consultant engineer having 13+ years of experience in System and Network infrastructure in general and Data Management basically.

Professional in backup systems using

various wide applications in backup And Disaster Recovery. Rock-solid experience with Active Directory Domain Services, Forest/Domain infrastructure on Windows Server including DNS Zones, Replication, GPOs, IP Security, Site-To-Site VPN and last but not least, Cisco Routers, Switches & ASA appliances.

Always seeking opportunities where I can continue to contribute to enterprise growth and technological expansion through change, update and improvement.

My willingness to stay with my Careers in IT make me shining in spite of the hard moments of challenges and issues.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### June2019 - Present

# **Backup and Disaster Recovery Admin**

**AIMS-KNG** Kuwait

- Achieved a Backup application design for Commvault software to cover all live servers (SAP HANA, Oracle, SQL, Exchange DAG,) and virtual desktop computers compatible with Huawei Systems.
- Achieved a successful a failover between three sites which led to avoid backup failure in the offline site, successfully gain synchronous between the brain node and the passive node.
- decrease the backup size in license yearly report by 25% from the last full backup used before upgrading systems.
- Strengthening realistic copying services by 4 auxiliary copies to multiple tape libraries and NAS storage in each site with different retention periods.
- Enable backup application to reach non-domain computers to be included in backup process. (using editing hosts file in both server and clients)
- Fixing disaster when happened by accomplish and tested efficiently. (using BC-Manager)
- Update CommVault application service package 11 version 14 and 19 to latest
   V.23 and complied with support requirements.

### July 2017 - Sep 2018

### **IT Representative and IT Manager**

**UIPM** Kuwait

- Designed and distributed network infrastructure installation for head office in Kuwait university CUP3 buildings.
- Established a new server Datacenter room and launched 8 servers using windows server 2016 for total infrastructure and Linux phone system.
- Eliminated traffic discontinuity by 80% through building end-to-end automatic antenna using Fortinet Firewall and bandwidth shaper for 400 users.
- $\cdot$  launched a Migration to office 365 email from Exchange 2013 for 400 users, updated all archived mailbox to the latest version.
- Built and Managed backup system for all servers and user data. (using Veritas net backup)
- Reduced project cost for calls by executed PPX internally and automated phone system.
- Coordinated between different departments to help company in purchase IT'S servers and storage and other network parts

#### JAN 2012 - June 2017

# **Senior System Engineer**

### Kharafi National Kuwait

- Led IT team from 4 Engineers and solved advanced issues registered by various users and advised accordingly to the team members.
- Connected Multi sites to head office using network configuration and VPN tunnel. (using Cisco routers)
- Helped users by launching DFS and automated script to users accessing file servers and print server in each site. (total 400 users)
- Upgraded system environment from windows server 2003 to windows server 2008.
- Built and Managed Backup & recovery for Servers Data. (Using Symantec backup)
- Reduced time in installation and setup systems by launching automatic deployment. (using SCCM).
- solved daily user's problems related to Active Directory policies and file server.
- Monitored and tested system performance and provided performance statistics and reports.
- Enhanced customer's mailing system by upgrading from exchange 2007 to exchange 2010. maintained and supported the physical and virtual IT environment and to improve it with new and enhanced services.

#### Skills

**Networking**: Cisco, VLAN, TCP/IP DHCP, SNMP, Network analysis, VOIP, PBX, Huawei, RRAS, CCNA and VPN.

## **Operating Systems:**

Microsoft windows server 2003,2008,2012,2016(advanced) Linux (Basic) MAC (Basic), Windows desktop XP,7,10.

### **Backup Software:**

CommVault (advanced), Veeam (Advanced), Veritas Net backup (Advanced) and HP.

### Hardware:

HP servers, Blade, Dell, IPM, Fujitsu, Compaq, EMC, Quantum Tape library and more.

#### Infrastructure:

Active Directory, DNS, DHCP, Exchange2013-2016, Office 365, DFS, Print and more.

## Virtualization:

Hyper V, VMware, AWS, Huawei and familiar about any other environment.

## **Projects**

Designed success small factory for ARABI company- Kuwait in the Sabhan area contains network infrastructure and Microsoft environment. IP telephones communicating head office to the new factory, office365, and Cisco firewall.

- Tested systems are working correctly and identifying, investigated and repairing any system faults.
- planned system upgrades and updated the existing Systems as per the plan.

### April 2011 - Dec 2011

# Network security engineer

Al-Dana Kuwait

- •Improved and planned engineer for new offers tenders and made pricing compatibility as per Budget stakeholders by matching needs with specifications.
- Designed network infrastructure in Arabi projects in Sabhan and delivered consultant reports for MOH ministry. (Details in project section)

## Feb 2009 - Jan 2011

## IT Manager

Oriental Resort Egypt-Sharm El-Sheikh

- Troubleshooted all hardware, software and network operating system.
- Provided Orientation, training, and support to all users of existing technology.
- Maintained and developed all IT infrastructure elements.
- Maintained current IT network and accurate inventory of Technology, hardware, software licenses and all IT resources.
- Monitored and maintained technology to ensure maximum utilization with optimum cost.
- Migrated windows server from 2000 to 2008 server with users' profiles and file server.
- Updated and configured Hotel management system from fidelio6 to suit 8 and network firewall from Isa 2004 and ISA 2006.
- Managed and maintained large server environment, especially those multiple data centers with active/active and active/passive configurations.
- Expansion wireless internet, configured and renewed access points to cover from rooms to the beach of resort.
- Solved problems of file and print servers and data access through policies.
- Managed a Project installation for building IT systems in the new branch of the resort in 2010 at Marsa-Alam.

# **Education & Certificates**

# B.SC. IN ELECTRONICS & COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING from Cairo University Egypt Awarded MAY 2007

Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate
Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator
Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer
CCNA Routing and switching
HCIA Huawei HCNA
HCIA Huawei HCNA
PMP Project Management
IELTS British council

Microsoft certified IT Professional

Windows Server 2016 **Oct** 11, 2018 Windows Server 2012 March 2, 2017 Windows Server 2008 May 29, 2013 Windows Server 2003 Dec 3, 2008 Cisco 2009 certificate cloud and Computing 2019 Huawei certificate Storage 2020 OCT - 2021 Level 3- 2021

https://mcp.microsoft.com/anonymous/transcript/validate User Transcript ID: 819966. access Code: 36363636